<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>David S. Neal</title>
 <link href="http://blog.davidsneal.co.uk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://blog.davidsneal.co.uk/"/>
 <updated>2014-06-07T23:57:00+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://blog.davidsneal.co.uk</id>
 <author>
   <name>David S. Neal</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>GitHub Pages and Jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://blog.davidsneal.co.uk/2014/06/07/jekyll-and-github-pages/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.davidsneal.co.uk/2014/06/07/jekyll-and-github-pages</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Considering this blog itself is powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, it seems quite fitting that my first post should be about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if GitHub doesn&amp;#39;t do enough for the developer community with its free Git repository functionality, you can also &lt;strong&gt;host a website with them for free!&lt;/strong&gt; No, I&amp;#39;m not joking, you can even use a custom domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to go ahead and get started the first thing you need to do is create a new repository. It must be named &lt;strong&gt;username.github.io&lt;/strong&gt;. &amp;#39;username&amp;#39; must be replaced with your GitHub username in order for it to work, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidsneal/davidsneal.github.io&quot;&gt;davidsneal.github.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clone your new repo locally, add some content and push it back up to the master branch. It&amp;#39;ll take a couple of minutes for the site to show up. Once your site is up and running, you&amp;#39;ll be impressed with the speed as you shall automatically be taking advantage of GitHub&amp;#39;s Content Delivery Network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the latest information regarding GitHub pages &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll takes plain text post files and transforms them into blog posts, such as the one you&amp;#39;re reading now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There a heck of a lot more to it than that, but that&amp;#39;s the main essence I have picked up over my short experience with it, dramatically condensed into a single sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve not got too far through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home/&quot;&gt;Jekyll documentation&lt;/a&gt; yet, but it seems very comprehensive and well explained. Serious kudos for the design of their site too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation took me a little longer than was made out, but &lt;strong&gt;Ruby&lt;/strong&gt; is still completely alien to me. I got held up on the very first step &lt;code&gt;gem install jekyll&lt;/code&gt;, receiving a message it appears many others have seen too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t have write permissions for the /Library/Ruby/Gems/2.0.0 directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a visit to stack&lt;strong&gt;overflow&lt;/strong&gt; I installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://rvm.io/&quot;&gt;Ruby Versions Manager&lt;/a&gt;, before returning to stack&lt;strong&gt;overflow&lt;/strong&gt;. Once I&amp;#39;d got that sorted Jekyll was a breeze to get running, and I had the base install site up and running in under a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some great Jekyll themes out there, for anyone wondering, this theme is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
